you better show me that one for approval
and i don't know why we did this so late
actually i do know why because i didn't
want to over
load you
yeah i didn't want to overload you with
information but i i do think it's better
to have a semi-western group so we
already started last time semi-western
look it puts your hand more underneath
the ball and especially now the reason
why i changed it was your actually your
elbow
i think it's easier on the elbow
the semi-western grip you know why
because with the eastern you were here
before and now look when you hit the
elbow is more behind the ball so when
you hit there's a little bit more
pressure on the elbow when you put your
hand underneath especially if you're
trying to topspin it places the elbow
more underneath the racket it places the
hand underneath the racket the elbow
more underneath the racket and when you
hit your forehand topspin it's a lot
easier on the arm so that's why we're
switching the grip to semi-western was
the i draw this for you last time for
the clinic were you able to stick to
this or
okay so i have to tell you what my brain
does go ahead tell me it's like
when you serve
yeah with this grip yeah
continental
international grip yeah yeah yeah yeah
it's just yeah it's awkward okay and now
now
this new grip is also like that feel oh
it feels weird yeah so now there is no
comfort whatsoever on uh it's okay it's
gonna be fine okay
i think your forehand last time we
played the beforehand looked so much
better yeah you draw some lines yeah and
then you put it you put it right here
out here yeah and just connect that make
sure you angle your hand off like this
right and now you just play it from here
it's the best grip in the world yeah
yeah no idea
i was at this clinic in the gallery yeah
and
i was like very fidgety okay so the
whole group is waiting for like the heat
and i'm like well it's going to take you
a while to it's going to take you a
while to find this grip so when you grab
the racket you're most likely going to
go to the old grip this is muscle memory
yeah but i already saw last time you're
hitting the forehand a lot better
look at this that's beautiful anna come
on
good normally when people switch to a
more like western grip they start
dumping balls into the net because
if you have let's say a continental grip
and you hit a ball your wrist is at a
certain angle yeah and you get used to
this angle and now if i turn my
racquet over to let's say semi western
you see the wrist is likely going to
stay at that same angle when you make
contact because of muscle memory but
look at the racket head it's very closed
so now what needs to happen is the wrist
needs to go more underneath so there's a
different position of the wrist so that
is what happens to most people when they
turn the grip over to more western grip
because that close racket faces start
dumping balls into the net
here's the crazy thing i didn't see that
from you last week the first time we
switched your grip you didn't really
dump anything into the net
so you're doing amazing it's actually
going opposite
right now but yes
but that's what you're seeing it's top
spin so the trajectory of the ball will
change with more top spin it's a lot
easier to make tops with a semi-western
grip and the ball will look more like
this it'll go up and then down yeah or
you're before your ball was a little bit
more straight like this right
so the way the ball will shape
itself over the net is going to change
with this grip i like your hat oh you
like it yeah i like it too the reason
why i'm wearing a hat i haven't gotten a
haircut in a while
you have really good style a lot of
comments is about your shoes all the
time people hey dude you're changing
them like gloves you know i have a lot
of style
no i'm just kidding i like your style
too okay let's continue here we go
and a beautiful forehand all right now
on the run
same thing you start right there
and finish it all make sure you finish
like what you normally do finish all the
way here now here's the thing you can do
you've been already doing this kind of
naturally
but you can when the swing is completely
done
you can put the put the racket in your
hand like this you see it's not that
you're trying to catch the racket over
here you just you're just going to tuck
this arm and you're going to place the
rack in your hand here and grab it
you're already doing this a little bit
i've seen you do it even in your match
but i want you to be a little bit more
conscious of it okay
it can reinforce a good finish just
don't catch it too early though
you see that that's what i don't like
this is why normally i don't instruct
players to catch the racket because
exactly what happened there
you're catching here remember what i
told you you're going to here
and here this is how you catch the
racquet you can't catch the racquet out
front because now you're going to
shorten the the finish
show me how to watch this girl here
look
here
yeah in here so the very end when the
racket's already done
you just put it in here like that
there you go beautiful anna come on
and it's clean very
clean that's beautiful what's your
favorite color you want red green orange
yellow blue red yeah yeah all right i
want you to go around this cone now
and go around the cone
there you go
good
oh
i love it two more come on
a little too close to the ball and give
me a match point give me a whip right
here whip
one more time my racket face slightly
opened up one more time anna come on
too far away you stopped too early don't
set your feet too early one more time
calm
and now you're being careful come on now
swing freely
all right one more time come on match
point pressure's on
okay a little bit short but it's okay
we'll do another round you're doing
great dana you're doing fantastic
very nice okay
okay again the grip we're gonna have to
hit like a couple of thousand forehands
so this becomes muscle memory yeah yeah
you have to be very patient you know
with cerebral people like me
no
yeah perfect you have to be perfect and
then what happens when you try to be
perfect or let's replace the word
perfect we're trying to get the ball in
at all costs
you actually tense up
and you start decelerating the most
important part of the forehand which is
the contact area and you start steering
and guiding and pushing the ball so it
happened a couple of times now here's
the frustrating thing when you do that
your intention is to get the ball in
really badly but you end up missing just
as much if not more right so i'm telling
you you have good mechanics
hit freely
very good top spin go around the cone
come on
oh look at this
love it nice body involvement there
good anna three more come on
and again a little bit more depth and
you're doing perfect
yikes all right no problem come again
good one more match points give me a
whip
anna this is incredible
come on
all right now we're going to remove the
cone we're going to try to rally back
and forth cross-court you and i are
against each other you want to take some
water take some pellegrino
of course i'm going to close that that
the trash can right there look it looks
so bad right i like perrier better i
don't really like filigree that much you
like perrier pellegrino is a little too
flat for me it is not bubbly enough
yeah this purified water
with artificially added
bubbles what yes no way pellegrina is
from the source no way yeah yeah it's
completely two different stores i didn't
know that
good
good anna
come again
swing freely
good
yeah i mean he spoke to me on the last
clinton yeah
he's like oh no you don't have to do all
of this like
going this way maybe you can just and
you just
you know held my hand i wouldn't i think
it's fine whatever you're doing here is
fine that's not the problem the problem
is around the contact zone you're still
steering sometimes you're not hitting
freely what i like you that's why i'm
doing the hand drill with you is to
accelerate here with the hand like this
just all you need is right here you need
freedom in this part right back here is
okay
there you go
come on skim my hand
there you go skim my hand
there it is
you're not going through my hands skim
it
there you go like this there you go do
it again
there you go come on again
there you go come on don't get stuck
underneath my hand either come on
there you go
that's all we need so around that
contact zone here i want to show you
here put your hand like this i'm going
to hit your hand very lightly don't
worry put your hand like you're the ball
yeah watch this
see how i'm skimming it
see i'm skipping on top of it you see
that i'm not going like this yes i'm
going i'm doing somebody's ass hey
you should do this
turn around okay
here
very simple it's so simple it's not even
funny
couldn't be more simple beforehand
good
again
how simple is that
don't get funky with it come on
i know you're getting funky with it
again keep it simple
come on
you get you're getting a little funky
again
come on now
i feel like you're over extending the
wrist you're going like this it's
unnecessary to go like this keep the
forehand technique simple don't over
complicate it
don't get funky with it yeah
simple
is the best
accelerate it don't steer
hit freely this is confusion sometimes
why i think
i think i have to
at the match it's at the
matching point
the matching point i feel like i have to
fill the proper no
you don't
position of my wrist nah it's going to
happen naturally the lucky thing that
you do that you have on the forehead not
just to anybody all of us when we hit
the ball the wrist extends and naturally
gives you stability naturally so there's
no need to stiffen the whole of the
racket there's also no need to loosen it
too much
natural is the best way as if you were
hitting the ball with your hand natural
oh okay because the wrist bends back it
gives this the ball impacts the
the string bed the wrist is already back
it gives natural stability so instead of
like to hold the racquet here the wrist
has to be stiff
so it doesn't go like this well it can't
be too loose
because then it gets sloppy and it might
move at contact but it shouldn't be too
stiff either because then it's too rigid
then it's moving like rigidly so
sometimes i see you overextending your
wrist i see you going like this i see
the racket going like this and you're
taking it back it's too rigid
now the wrist won't what they call lag
properly because it's too stiff here so
it can't be too stiff can't be too loose
just keep it natural
like you're doing you did like probably
a hundred four hands at least today the
correct way so yes
well
which i'm
waiting for we're waiting to get like
i'm waiting for you to give me like 10
15 20 ball rallies we're getting like
four or five six ball rallies i'm
looking for those 10 to 15 to 20 ball
rallies that's our next step let me
guide you through it
again on my finger all right go ahead no
no not permanent here we go here
here
don't take it down you see you see yeah
oh so it's okay one more time
you're not gonna feel this too much it's
gonna happen fast so you're going to go
here and now it's going to happen fast
here
that part of the stroke is going to be
fast
that's going to happen by itself i know
you're worried about that part right now
but you can't manufacture that part
that's the risk changing positions in
the forward phase
or what's called the wrist lag it'll
happen by itself if you try to make it
happen
you gotta you're in a world of trouble
because now you're gonna just ignore it
ignore it completely
high-level players don't know that that
part of the forehand happens completely
happens on its own it's already
happening on its own but with you but if
you try to tinker with it you start
making the wrist go like this on like
consciously you start going like here
now you you make that part of the
forehand slower you slow it down in
order to make certain things happen and
now you got a hitch in your forehand and
it's not going to be continuous it's not
going to accelerate the same way okay so
don't think about it okay all right here
we go come on
good anna
better proper spacing
good finish all the way
good
good anna
on
good okay go there i'm going to feed you
some more
this time i'm going to be hand fed even
easier
good
nice work this is the only way to do it
muscle memory we have to hit thousands
upon thousands of forehands for your
wrist to get used to this new grip we
have to work hard i'm excited we have to
grind you're doing good you know you
know what i love the whole time you have
a smile on your face when you play
you like to play right yeah i can see it
you look happy while you play
and that's really all it's all that's
what it's all about you haven't you're
having fun
and even when you're missing you're
smiling it's amazing
nice work anna good job